Guide to the Civil War Photograph File 1861-1865, [1880-1889] PR 164
New-York Historical Society
- Series VI: Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the War
  - Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the War: Plates 81-89 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 93)
    Plate 84 - View of the Interior of Fort Stedman
    Plate 85 - Blandford Church, Petersburg
    Plate 86 - Interior view of Confederate Works at Gracie's Salient
    Plate 87 - Dutch Gap Canal, James River
    Plate 88 - Ruins of Richmond and Petersburg Railroad, across the James
    Plate 89 - Libby Prison, Richmond
  - Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the War: Plates 91-92, 99-100 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 94)
    Plate 91 - Ruins of Arsenal, Richmond
    Plate 92 - View on Canal, near Haxall & Crenshaw's Mill, Richmond
    Plate 99 - McLean's House, where Grant & Lee signed the Capitulation
    Plate 100 - Dedication of Monument, on Bull Run Battle-field
  - Gardner's Photographic Sketch Book of the War: Text pages (Offsite-box 9, Folder 95)
- Series VII: Naval Scenes and Sites
  Series VII includes a mammoth plate photograph of the U.S. Iron Clad Ram, Dictator, which was designed by John Ericcson and built at the Delamater Iron Works in New York. The monitor-class boat was 320 feet long with two guns and a ram at both ends. Sent to the assault on Fort Fisher, the boat had mechanical problems and returned to port. Eventually decommissioned, the Dictator was sold for scrap in 1883.
  - U.S.S. Wabash, undated (Offsite-box 10, Folder 96)
  - U.S. Iron Clad Ram Dictator, at Delameter Iron Works, New York, photograph by J. H. Beals & Co., 1863 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 107)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Offsite-box 10, Folder 97)
- Series VIII: Relief Organizations
  Series VIII includes a view of a field tent of the Christian Commission, as well as two images of the New York Women's Central Relief Organization, in which well-dressed women sort relief supplies in a storefront near Cooper Union
  - Christian Commission, 1863 Aug (Offsite-box 10, Folder 98)
  - Women's Central Relief Association, New York (2 images), 1864-1865 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 99)
  - Volunteer Refreshment Saloon, Philadelphia, 1864-1865 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 100)
- Series IX: Later Platinum and other Prints
  Series IX holds photographs printed after the war; generally these were printed in the 1880s.
  - Photographs printed after 1865, [1880-1889] (Offsite-box 10, Folder 101-103)
- Oversize Photographs
  - From Series I: War Scenes and Sites
    - South Carolina--Fort Sumter, 1865 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 103)
  - From Series II: Portraits
    - Composite - Cartes de visite of military officers and statesmen; collection of O.H. Oldroyd of Columbus, Ohio, 1866 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 104)
    - Composite - General R.E. Lee and Staff by Rockwell and Cowell, 1866 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 104)
    - Composite - Soldiers' Fair in Springfield, MA, December 22, 1864, By J.C. Spoone, 1865 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 104)
    - Group - Field - 12th Regiment of New York Infantry, 1865 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 105)
    - Group - Studio - General S.W. Crawford and staff, undated (Offsite-box 11, Folder 106)
    - Group - Studio - General A.B. Burnside and staff, undated (Offsite-box 11, Folder 106)
    - Group - Studio - General U.S. Grant and staff, undated (Offsite-box 11, Folder 106)
  - From Series VII: Naval Scenes and Sites
    - U.S. Iron Clad Ram Dictator, at Delameter Iron Works, New York, photograph by J. H. Beals & Co., 1863 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 107)